<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-11-05T00:34:21+00:00</updated><id>/</id><title type="html">DREU 2018</title><subtitle>Hello! This blog is for documenting my summer 2018 DREU experience. Please don't mind the site  being under construction as I familiarize myself with developing, designing, and updating!</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Week 10</title><link href="/2018/09/10/week-10.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 10" /><published>2018-09-10T22:44:22+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-10T22:44:22+00:00</updated><id>/2018/09/10/week-10</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2018/09/10/week-10.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/week10.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;flying home&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Flying home, plane over Minneapolis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am posting this way after my actual week 10 of research, but with memories and insights that have lasted! Week 10 went by the fastest of them all– I sent in my project for evaluation and a paper for CHI with my name on it. I spent this last week writing up my project report, saying my goodbyes, and presenting my experience at our last HCI lab meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve never missed home more in my life, but I’ve also seen so much value in my 10 weeks in Iowa City. I’ve learned so much from Kyle, not only about accessibility research, but also from her leadership, kindness, and wisdom. Back in Washington, my perspective has changed with the awareness of accessibility and that is something I’m proud to take away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;you can view my individual project report &lt;a href=&quot;https://wangamelia.github.io/images/Project%20Report.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;
and my presentation slides &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1nGmn2Itf1BPBB9y3LJ-d3qW2wP5v_jc9-89uie6lkPg/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For website display purposes for the CRA-W organization, &lt;a href=&quot;https://wangamelia.github.io/images/amelia_dreu_website.tar.gz&quot;&gt;clicking here&lt;/a&gt; will download the tar file that contains this website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you Kyle Rector, the University of Iowa, and the Computing Research Association for this experience!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Flying home, plane over Minneapolis</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Week 09</title><link href="/2018/09/02/week-09.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 09" /><published>2018-09-02T22:44:22+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-02T22:44:22+00:00</updated><id>/2018/09/02/week-09</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2018/09/02/week-09.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/week09.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;View after hurricane&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;My view after the hurricane– it was only 7pm!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week, lots happened inside and outside the lab. I got back to work, wrapped up my personal project, got sick, and I experienced my first hurricane warning. The weather was awful for a few hours, but thankfully it just passed through. I was also indoors the whole time, and we were just directed to find lowest ground and wait it out. I also got a nice picture of the sky afterwards!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting sick really hindered my development which was hard to accept this week, especially being my second to last week in Iowa and my project needs to get evaluated by others. I spent then usual amount of time in lab but things were moving much slower and progress became so much more difficult. Kyle was able to test out my project remotely as she was in Mountain View for the week and gave me really valuable feedback. So even though I wasn’t able to keep adding new features, I feel that my code is much more robust and what I currently have has been able to improve a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week is my final week! I will mostly be working on my project report, which I’ll link on this website when I’m done. I cannot believe how fast this summer went by, and I’m sad that I’ll have to leave the friends I’ve made in this short time.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">My view after the hurricane– it was only 7pm!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Week 08</title><link href="/2018/08/24/week-08.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 08" /><published>2018-08-24T22:44:22+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-24T22:44:22+00:00</updated><id>/2018/08/24/week-08</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2018/08/24/week-08.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/week08.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;View of Chi City&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Chicago! It’s been so long since I’ve seen skyscrapers!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am in Chicago this weekend with my family, so it’s been a short break from the lab. We spent some time this week going over the interview transcriptions from the team project and brainstormed themes to discuss in the paper. Development for my personal project continues, and I am sending out it out for testing next week! I ran into an issue that set my progress back another day, as I couldn’t figure out why NVDA wasn’t working the way it had been previously. This was a good lesson though because after lots of reading forums, uninstalling, reinstalling, and paranoia, I regrouped with Kyle and found that a bug in my add-on was the cause of all of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have only two weeks left here, so I’ll be finishing up my projects, testing them, and writing a final report to link on this site.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Chicago! It’s been so long since I’ve seen skyscrapers!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Week 07</title><link href="/2018/08/18/week-07.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 07" /><published>2018-08-18T22:44:22+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-18T22:44:22+00:00</updated><id>/2018/08/18/week-07</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2018/08/18/week-07.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/week07.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My dorm door&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;My dorm door&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week, I went to a graduate student orientation event with Kyle and got to meet people in the department, including her incoming PhD students! There will be four total, all women in HCI which has been super exciting and inspiring to see. I also got a roommate this week as students are moving in for the school year (which starts in a few days). It’s been really nice to have company around and understand the campus more. Next week, my family is visiting and we’re going to take a quick weekend trip to Chicago as well as take a look at the university! I’ve missed them a lot, and I think the timing works out well to give me a boost right before I’ll be wrapping things up here in Iowa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the end of week 7– I’ve made progress on add-on development, my project proposal, and I’m finally done with video coding! The add on has to be written in python, which I have very little experience in, but this means making progress feels even more rewarding as I’m learning so much along the way. I have a little bit more time to work on development before an expert in accessible technology will test it out and evaluate it at the end of the month. There’s a lot to look forward to, and the weeks are moving quick!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">My dorm door</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Week 06</title><link href="/2018/08/12/week-06.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 06" /><published>2018-08-12T22:44:22+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-12T22:44:22+00:00</updated><id>/2018/08/12/week-06</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2018/08/12/week-06.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/week06.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hilarious photo I found on the department bulletin board&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;hilarious photo I found on the department bulletin board&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The weeks are flying by! We’re getting 3 videos done a day– more than halfway done. As for my personal project, I’ve been focusing on PyCharm as an IDE that is lacking in accessibility. It is important to improve existing IDEs/systems to be more accessible rather than creating new/seperate ones to not only allow these users to integrate and participate as a social responsibility, but to give these users the same options and advantages that sighted ones do– especially with sophisticated products with such a visual emphasis like typical IDEs. More details are discussed in my project proposal, which I’ll attach on my week 10 report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So as I said earlier, we are more than half way done with our video coding for the team project, but as I’m on a different timeline from the regular students, this was the other undergrad assistant’s last week. So we will see how this goes, me currently being the only active member on both projects! Kyle is also getting her new PhD students next week, so I’m excited to see new faces around the lab.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">hilarious photo I found on the department bulletin board</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Week 05</title><link href="/2018/08/05/week-05.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 05" /><published>2018-08-05T22:44:22+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-05T22:44:22+00:00</updated><id>/2018/08/05/week-05</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2018/08/05/week-05.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/week05.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;sunset in new dorm&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;sunset in new dorm&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have officially hit our halfway mark, and this week has been a big week to signify it. The first half hasn’t felt too short, but planning the next few weeks really makes me realize how little time I have left here! This week I also made the move to a new building on campus to get ready for the University’s fall semester, and I’m excited to see the area become more active.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We finally finished coding our videos for Cohen’s Kappa, and we decided to remove three labels from our codebook. Here is a snippet of the results and some of the labels that did/didn’t make the cut:
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cohen_sample.png&quot; alt=&quot;cohen snippet&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of them was a yes/no type which was surprising to get rid of because I thought agreement would be easy, but the low number of options also caused chance to play a much bigger factor. On the bright side, coding videos has become much easier!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that most of the heavier work on this project is over, I can focus more on my personal project! Up until now I’ve been reading up on issues in programming IDEs for blind users and various research in pursuit of making them more accessible, and I’ll get to start and try to develop something on my own. More details on that in the next few weeks!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">sunset in new dorm</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Week 04</title><link href="/2018/07/28/week-04.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 04" /><published>2018-07-28T22:44:22+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-28T22:44:22+00:00</updated><id>/2018/07/28/week-04</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2018/07/28/week-04.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/week04.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;code brainstorm on whiteboard&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;code brainstorm on whiteboard&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re almost at our half way mark, and I am getting used to life in this city! Soon I’ll have to prepare to move dorms and experience the start of the new semester– this school starts a whole month earlier than UW so it’ll be cool to get to see the different environments!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week, we want to be able to discuss Cohen’s Kappa for our video codes. Cohen’s Kappa is an agreement statistic for qualitative coding that takes into account agreement by chance. So this week, we had about 4-5 business days to label seven videos (I came in on the weekend to lighten up my daily load). Thankfully I can say I learned from my data exporting mishap last week and practiced saving my data frequently. I’m excited to see the results, and our work get turned into some cool statistics.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">code brainstorm on whiteboard</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Week 03</title><link href="/2018/07/20/week-03.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 03" /><published>2018-07-20T22:44:22+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-20T22:44:22+00:00</updated><id>/2018/07/20/week-03</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2018/07/20/week-03.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/week03.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mural under construction downtown&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;mural under construction downtown&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week, my cousin came to visit so I got to try out a lot a lot of restaurants and activities downtown… which is about two blocks away from campus!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back at the lab, I started to put together a project proposal document surrounding accessibility in programming. I am learning the ropes of NVDA, a open source screen reader, as well as developing an add-on for eclipse!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the video coding project, we had to meet three times this week– some labels were so subjective that we had to discuss their definitions and purposes many times before we could move forward. Also for our last meeting, BORIS crashed as I was exporting the data that I was supposed to bring and discuss. This should’ve been expected as I mentioned last week it was pretty buggy but my lesson was learned and I now try to save my projects as frequently as possible to avoid this cliche disaster…&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">mural under construction downtown</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Week 02</title><link href="/2018/07/14/week-02.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 02" /><published>2018-07-14T22:44:22+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-14T22:44:22+00:00</updated><id>/2018/07/14/week-02</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2018/07/14/week-02.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/week02.png&quot; alt=&quot;view through cs building 2nd floor&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;view through cs building 2nd floor&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Week two kicked into gear with project brainstorming and learning about video coding. I read a lot on different areas of accessibility and HCI to focus on for this summer, and honestly the decision-making was overwhelming. I feel like I have such little experience in this specific category but I’m excited to get started and see how things turn out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For video coding, the team met and first brainstormed things to label as kids played the exer-game. After agreeing on ~15 possible categories, we moved onto testing them out on one participant. One participant needs at least one label per category for each ball played during the session– and there were roughly 60 balls per session… One 18-minute video took over two hours to label! But this should get easier as we get used to the system. We used the free BORIS software to do this, and although it was a comprehensive and convieniently free service, using it came with many bugs. Nonetheless, we will get through the next 30 videos over the course of a month or so to analyze the data which should be exciting.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">view through cs building 2nd floor</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Week 01</title><link href="/2018/07/07/week-01.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 01" /><published>2018-07-07T22:44:22+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-07T22:44:22+00:00</updated><id>/2018/07/07/week-01</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2018/07/07/week-01.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/week01.png&quot; alt=&quot;sunset over the capitol building&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;sunset over the capitol building&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with adjusting to life in Iowa City, I spent my first week gathering knowledge and context to an existing research project that I am joining. It surrounds the implications of lack of accessible exercise for blind people, and addresses the issue by developing, designing, and evaluating an exer-game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I met with my team, which is led by a graduated master’s student who is leaving halfway through the summer. I am the only DREU student, but there is one other undergrad my age working with us so we have a lot to learn together!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am excited to delve more into HCI and computing research through a lens that I haven’t really had any experience in. Kyle has done extensive work in accessibility, mainly surrounding blind people, so I am excited for what’s to come.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">sunset over the capitol building</summary></entry></feed>